<?xml version="1.0"?>

<document>

  <properties>
    <title>Getting Started with JAMSEL</title>
    <author email="jawaid.hakim@codestreet.com">Jawaid Hakim</author>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <section name="Getting Started with JAMSEL">
      <p>
        This document (as well as the others in this section) provide
        an introduction to JAMSEL and how to use it within a project.
        For those that have already skimmed the documentation on this
        site, you may be asking yourself, what *exactly* does it mean to
        use JAMSEL? These documents attempt to illustrate how one might 
	install, integrate and leverage the power of Selector in a project.
      </p>

      <p>
        To avoid overwhelming you (user, developer, or contributor) with
        unnecessary information, this document attempts to provide
        references to various documents depending upon your MessageForge
        interests.  It is meant to provide you with a starting point
        that can be effectively used to get to the information you need
        without going through all of the documentation on the site,
        which might be a little overwhelming.
      </p>

      <subsection name="Overview of the Getting Started Documentation">
        <table>
          <tr><th>Document</th><th>Description</th></tr>
          <tr><td><a href="start/download.html">Download</a></td>
            <td>
              Before you can start using Selectorin any form, you'll have
              to download the Selectordistribution to your system (unless
              you plan on building Maven from source).  This document
              provides links to the various distributions available.
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr><td><a href="start/install.html">Install</a></td>
            <td>
              After you have downloaded a distribution, you'll need to
              install this on your system before you can start using
              JAMSEL (unless you plan on building Selectorfrom source).
              This document provides step-by-step instructions on the
              installation process.
            </td>
          </tr>
	  <!--
          <tr><td><a href="start/integrate.html">Integrate</a></td>
            <td>
              If you are interested in integrating Selectorwith your
              project, this document will provide such information.  The
              document details the process of creating a Maven project
              descriptor for your project.  This document provides
              example build files and project descriptors.
            </td>
          </tr>
	  -->
          <tr><td><a href="start/use.html">Use</a></td>
            <td>
              For those of you that have been referred to this document
              because you are trying to build a project that used JAMSEL, 
	      this document will provide you with all of the necessary information 
	      required to build any Maven-enabled project.
            </td>
          </tr>
        </table>
      </subsection>
    </section>
 </body>
</document>
